双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译    Barossa
翻译    北落师门
翻译    旧镇老翁
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译   泰温公爵
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
校对   夏大猫子
校对   临冬城的狮子
派
Pyke
克
城
派
Pyke
克
城
复校   屈畅(ccxx)  守誓剑
复校   pksunking    唐朝栗子
临冬城 Winterfell
精校  龙的命根子
时间轴   加文·维斯特林
后期   加文·维斯特林
策划   baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
颤抖海 Shivering Sea
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
魁尔斯Qarth
权力的游戏
第二季 第四集
衣柜字幕组
本字幕适用于第四集AVS REPACK修正版
（AVS第一版于33分钟处有6秒钟的片源缺失）
第四集  “骸骨花园”
"Garden of Bones"
必然是魔山  他块头最大
It's got to be the Mountain.He's the biggest.
- 他最强壮了  - 蠢牛的块头比狮子大
- He's the strongest.  - Bulls are bigger than lions.
但我可不会把注压在一只蠢牛上
Doesn't mean I'd pick a bull in a fight.
如果蠢牛有利爪尖牙  我就会
If the bull had fangs and claws, I would.
嗯  魔山或者我们的詹姆
Right, the Mountain or our man Jaime.
如果他还能出来的话
If he ever gets out.
洛拉斯·提利尔如何？
Loras Tyrell?
洛拉斯·提利尔？他比太后都漂亮
Loras Tyrell.He's prettier than the queen.
我才不管他漂不漂亮
I don't care about pretty.
他使剑比他们任何一个都厉害
He's better with a sword than any of them.
他能有多厉害？
How good could he be?
他在蓝礼·拜拉席恩背后耍剑好多年了
He's been stabbing Renly Baratheon for years,
而蓝礼还没死
and Renly ain't dead.
你看那些马是不是有些受惊了？
The horses seem a little spooked to you?
马嘛
They're horses.
连自己的影子都怕
They get spooked by their own shadows.
嘘
Shh.
你听见没？
Do you hear that?
没啊
No.
那边好像有动静
There's something out there.
啊
Oh.
噢  你这混球
Oh, you're a right little prick.
你该瞧瞧你那熊样
You should see your face.
我敢说你都会笑疯的
I swear you pissed yourself.
“噢  谁在那 喔！”
"Oh, who goes there?Ahh!"
那边好像真有动静
There is something out there.
真是  还想和我玩这套
Yeah, don't even try me.
- 瑞尼克  - 你以为我是白痴啊？
- Rennick.  - Do you think I'm an idiot?
- 瑞尼克!
- Rennick!
- 北境之王万岁！  - 北境之王万岁！
- King in the North!  - The King in the North!
我们伤亡的人数是兰尼斯特的五分之一
Five Lannisters dead for every one of ours.
罗柏·史塔克
北境之王
他们都死了 扒下他们的东西吧
They're dead.Take everything they've got.
我们没地方关押所有这些俘虏
We've nowhere to keep all these prisoners.
粮草都不够自己吃
Barely enough food to feed our own.
卢斯·波顿
恐怖堡伯爵
我们不会处决俘虏的  波顿大人
We're not executing prisoners, Lord Bolton.
当然  陛下
Of course, Your Grace.
军官们将很有价值
The officers will be useful.
他们中的某些应该知晓泰温·兰尼斯特的计划
Some of them may be privy to Tywin Lannister's plans.
我很怀疑
I doubt it.
无论如何 我们很快就知道了
Well, we'll learn soon enough.
在我家族有句古谚“裸体的人少有秘密
In my family we say,"A naked man has few secrets.
但剥皮的人没有秘密”
A flayed man none."
在北境  我父亲禁止剥皮行为
My father outlawed flaying in the North.
- 我们现在不在北境啊  - 我们不会对他们用刑
- We're not in the North.  - We're not torturing them.
荣誉之道看上去很美
The high road's very pretty,
但打起仗来荣誉可就碍事了
but you'll have a hard time marching your army down it.
兰尼斯特也扣着人质
The Lannisters hold prisoners of their own.
我绝不会给他们借口来虐待我的妹妹们
I won't give them an excuse to abuse my sisters.
不  不  不要！不要！
No, no, don't! Don't!
- 嘘  嘘  - 求您了！
- Shh, shh.- Please!
嘘
Shh.
感染了
The rot's set in.
不  不要！不 不要！
No, don't!No, don't!
- 嘘  - 求您了  不要！
- Shh.- Please, don't!
这伤口会好的  这其实一点都不疼
It'll get better.It doesn't even hurt.
如果不截肢的话，感染会扩散的——
The rot will spread.If we don't take the foot now--
不  你不要
No, you can't!
大人！求求您 大人
Ser! Please, Ser.
- 我不能没了--  - 她不动手术你就会没命的
- I can't lose--  - You'll die if she don't do it.
我不想变成瘸子 求您了
I don't want to be a cripple, please.
我的手下肯定比这毛头更需要你的照料
Surely one of our men needs your attention more than this cub.
您的手下我不负责  大人
Your men are not my men, My Lord.
把这咬在嘴里躺好  你不会想看的
Put this in your mouth and lie down.You don't want to watch.
- 不！你不能！ - 咬住
- No! You can't!  - Bite on it.
总比咬断你自己的舌头好 相信我
It's better than biting your own tongue, believe me.
- 你叫什么名字？  - 泰丽莎
- What's your name?  - Talisa.
姓呢？
Your last name?
你想知道我的家族为谁而战？
You want to know what side my family fights on?
你知道我的姓氏  这可不公平哦
You know my family name.You have me at a disadvantage.
那孩子因你的军令而丢了腿
That boy lost his foot on your orders.
他们杀了我父亲
They killed my father.
- 那个男孩干的？  - 是他效忠的家族
- That boy did?  - The family he fights for.
你以为他和乔佛里国王是朋友？
Do you think he's friends with King Joffrey?
他不过是个兰尼斯港边的渔夫之子
He's a Fisherman's son that grew up near Lannisport.
他大概还从没碰过长枪
He probably never held a spear
直到几个月前他们硬塞给他了一支
before they shoved one in his hands a few months ago.
我并不记恨这孩子
I have no hatred for the lad.
真希望这话能让他的脚长回来
That should help his foot grow back.
你要我们投降  终止这些屠戮
You'd have us surrender, end all this bloodshed.
我懂  那样国家又能回归到和平
I understand.The country would be at peace
而人民又会在正义的
and life would be just under the righteous hand
好国王乔佛里手下快乐的生活
of good King Joffrey.
- 你会杀了乔佛里？  - 如果诸神能赐予我力量的话
- You're going to kill Joffrey?  - If the Gods give me strength.
- 接下来呢？  - 我不知道
- And then what?  - I don't know.
我们会回到临冬城
We'll go back to Winterfell.
我对铁王座没有任何欲望
I have no desire to sit on the Iron Throne.
那谁有？
So who will?
我不知道
I don't know.
你为推翻一个国王而战斗
You're fighting to overthrow a king,
然而你却对推翻之后没有任何设想？
and yet you have no plan for what comes after?
赢下战争才有之后
First we have to win the war.
你还没说你来自哪呢
You never told me where you're from.
- 瓦兰提斯  - 瓦兰提斯？
- Volantis.  - Volantis?
瓦兰提斯  位于狭海对岸的东方大陆厄索斯 自由贸易城邦之一
你背井离乡好远啊
You're far from home.
那孩子能碰见你真是走了大运
The boy was lucky you were here.
他碰见你也是走了“大运”
He was unlucky that you were.
你哥哥又有新的叛国罪行 你得为此认罪伏法
You're here to answer for your brother's latest treasons.
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
国王
陛下
Your Grace,
珊莎·史塔克
我跟我那叛徒哥哥一点关系都没有
whatever my traitor brother has done, I had no part.
您知道的  求求您  请——
You know that.I beg you--
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
蓝赛尔爵士   告诉她  她哥哥做了些什么好事
Ser Lancel, tell her of this outrage.
你哥哥以卑鄙的巫术
Using some vile sorcery,
控制成群恶狼 攻击史戴佛·兰尼斯特爵士
your brother fell on Stafford Lannister with an army of wolves.
其麾下数千壮士在睡梦中横遭屠戮
Thousands of good men were butchered.
蓝塞尔·兰尼斯特
骑士 凯冯·兰尼斯特之子
瑟曦、詹姆和提利昂的堂弟
曾任劳勃一世的随从
屠杀之后 北方人用被害者的血肉
After the slaughter,the northmen feasted on
大开筵席
the flesh of the slain.
杀了你就能给你的老哥提个醒了
Killing you would send your brother a message.
但我老娘坚持要留你性命
But my mother insists on keeping you alive.
起来
Stand.
所以我们要换个方式
So we'll have to send your brother
给你老哥提个醒
a message some other way.
马林
Meryn.
不要打脸
Leave her face.
马林·特兰
骑士 御林铁卫
我要她漂漂亮亮
I like her pretty.
马林  我的未婚妻穿的太多啦
Meryn, My Lady is overdressed.
帮她脱了
Unburden her.
如果你希望罗柏·史塔克能听见
If you want Robb Stark to hear us,
我们就还要再弄大些动静
we're going to have to speak louder.
这是在干什么？
What is the meaning of this?
什么样的骑士会殴打无助的少女?
What kind of Knight beats a helpless girl?
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 代理首相
为国王效命的骑士，小恶魔
The kind who serves his King, Imp.
现在 你们招子放亮点
Careful, now. We don't want
波隆
都城守备队长
否则这身漂亮白袍就要沾血了
to get blood all over your pretty white cloak.
谁给这女孩找点东西遮体?
Someone get the girl something to cover herself with.
这女孩是你未来的王后
She is to be your queen.
你就不在乎她的名誉?
Have you no regard for her honor?
- 我在惩罚她  - 她可有罪?
- I'm punishing her.  - For what crimes?
她和她哥哥的战斗毫无瓜葛 你这二货
She did not fight her brother's battle, you half-wit.
你不能这样跟我说话  我是国王  想干什么就于什么!
You can't talk to me like that.The king can do as he likes!
疯王想干什么就干什么
The Mad King did as he liked.
你詹姆舅舅就没有告诉你他的下场?
Has your Uncle Jaime ever told you what happened to him?
没人敢在御林铁卫的面前威胁国王陛下
No one threatens his Grace in the presence of the Kingsguard.
我不是在威胁国王 爵士
I'm not threatening the King, Ser.
我是在教育外甥
I am educating my nephew.
波隆 如果马林爵士再开口的话 宰了他
Bronn, the next time Ser Meryn speaks, kill him.
这才叫威胁 明白区别了么
That was a threat.See the difference?
我为我外甥的行为向你道歉
I apologize for my nephew's behavior.
请实话实说
Tell me the truth.
你希望终止婚约么？
Do you want an end to this engagement?
我忠实于乔佛里陛下 他是我唯一的真爱
I am loyal to King Joffrey,my one true love.
史塔克小姐 也许你能比我们活得都长
Lady Stark, you may survive us yet.
小国王真是脑残
The little king's backed up.
这小子从蛋到脑子都秀逗了
Clogged from balls to brains.
你觉得开开荤能治愈他么
You think dipping his wick will cure what ails him?
脑残没得治
There's no cure for being a cunt.
但他毕竟不大点儿
But the boy's at that age.
而且他实在太无聊了 只能揪揪苍蝇翅膀
And he's got nothing to do all day but pick wings off flies.
或许排点"毒素"也不孬
Couldn't hurt to get some of the poison out.
你在这里干嘛 狗儿
What are you doing here, dog?
你舅舅送你一个命名日礼物
Your uncle left your nameday present
让我一定要交给你
and asked me to see that you got it.
然后呢
And?
是什么？
What is it?
请进，陛下
Look inside,Your Grace.
国王陛下
Your Grace.
－命名日快乐 陛下 －我的命名日已经过了
- Happy nameday, Your Grace. - My nameday has passed.
您不提 我们就可以假装不知道啊
We won't tell if you won't.
萝丝
不
No.
她
Her.
摸她去
Touch her.
你能不能打她？
Could you hit her?
我舅舅送你们来的？
My uncle sent you?
是的陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
他亲自挑选的我们
He chose us himself.
哦
Hmm.
用这个
Use this.
使劲
Harder.
我说了要使劲
I said harder.
他会希望看到 我没让他白花钱的
He'd want me to get his money's worth.
陛下，太痛就没快感可言了
Your Grace, too much pain will spoil the pleasure.
求求您 求求您
Please, please
求求您， 陛下
please, Your Grace.
陛下，如果你的舅舅知道了——
Your Grace,if your uncle finds out--
我就是想让他知道
Oh, I want him to find out.
结束后你带她去他房间
You will bring her to his chambers when you're finished
然后让他瞧瞧你都做了什么
and show him what you've done.
否则 你做的孽换你来受
Or the same thing will happen to you.
开始
Begin.
使劲！
Harder!
哟，这不是我最爱的皮条公嘛
Well, if it isn't my favorite whoremonger.
没让你久等吧
Pray I haven't kept you waiting long.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”  财政大臣
陛下
Your Grace.
你这是来为兰尼斯特开价的 对么？
Now you do the Lannisters' bidding, is that it?
说说看  是不是我哥哥尸骨未寒
Tell me, was my brother's body even cold
你就找到新靠山了？
before you secured your newest patron?
我是一个现实的人
I'm a practical man.
蓝礼·拜拉席恩
在高庭的王
就是不怎么忠诚
Just not a loyal one.
那您想让我忠实于谁呢？
And who would you have me be loyal to?
您哥哥的尸体？
Your brother's corpse?
我不喜欢你，贝里席大人
I don't like you,Lord Baelish.
我不喜欢你这副嘴脸
I don't like your face.
我不喜欢听你掏浆糊
I don't like the words that come oozing out of your mouth.
我不想让你在我的营帐里多待哪怕一分钟
I don't want you in my tent one minute more than necessary.
告诉我 你来这里做什么？
So tell me,why are you here?
你可以信任布蕾妮
You can trust Brienne.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
她的忠诚可不收费
Her loyalty comes without charge.
您在御前会议上还有朋友，陛下
You still have many friends at court, Your Grace,
他们相信奈德·史塔克的失败
many who believe Ned Stark erred
是由于没有听从您的建议
by not supporting your claim.
现在我明白了
Now I understand.
你知道我大军势众
You know I have the numbers.
你知道我正向君临进军
You know I'm marching on King's Landing.
等我大权在握 你希望你屁股不挪窝
When I take the throne,you hope to retain your position.
脑袋也不搬家
And your head.
我当然要为我的性命竭尽心智
I would give priority to my head.
我很清楚您不怎待见我
I understand that you don't like me,
这的确让我非常犯愁
and while that saddens me greatly,
可我今日来此并非要讨您欢心
I did not come here today seeking your affection.
等您挥师君临
When you march on King's Landing,
久攻不下时 自要讨一记闭门羹 然而那门关得——
you may find yourself facing a protracted siege or...
或许并不严实
open gates.
陛下
Your Grace.
贝里席大人
Lord Baelish.
这些帐篷在我眼里都长一个样
All of these tents look the same to me.
玛格丽·提利尔
王后 梅斯·提利尔之女
- 能不能请您——  —我很乐意
- Would you be so kind-- - it would be my pleasure.
我也花了好几星期才搞清楚营地的路线
It took me weeks to learn way around the camp.
甚至有两次我在别人更衣的时候闯了进去
Twice I walked in on officers in stages of undress.
然而我刚搞清楚哪个帐篷是我的
And the moment I learn which tent is mine,
我们却又要拔营了
we're on the move again.
您的帐篷？
Your tent?
不是"我们"的帐篷？
Not our tent?
也许是因为国王打鼾？
The King snores, perhaps?
或者 他喜爱独处？
Or simply prefers solitude?
毫无疑问 是军务烦劳所致
Pressures of command, no doubt.
4位国王争夺江山
Four kings vying for the throne.
即便我不懂战争
I am not tutored in warfare,
但我懂基本的算术 越多军队 越有利
but basic arithmetic favors the side with the greater numbers.
若战争就是算术
If war were arithmetic,
那数学家就该统治世界了
the mathematicians would rule the world.
我注意到您哥哥刚才进了国王的营帐
But I did notice your brother entering his Grace's tent the just now.
御林铁卫本就应该长随君王左右
The place of a Kingsguard is by the King's side.
那么在婚礼的那晚
And on the night of the your wedding,
伴随君王之人 是谁呢？
who was by the King's side then?
你似乎对我们的婚姻很感兴趣
You seem quite interested in our marriage.
不仅仅是我
Your marriage is quite interesting...
整个王国都对你们的婚姻很感兴趣
Not only to me, but to the realm.
它的有趣之处在于 富家女的婚姻
The marriage of a wealthy girl always breeds interest,
总是该诞生点什么才对……
if nothing else.
你从未结婚 是吧？
You've never married, have you?
我的感情一直都很不幸 真可悲
I've been unlucky in my affections, sadly.
确实可悲
That is sad.
不过这样也许也不错
Though perhaps it's for the best.
看起来婚姻观念让你困惑不解了
The whole notion of marriage seems to confuse you,
请让我来解释
so allow me to explain.
在朝从君 在家从夫 这就是我的婚姻
My husband is my King, and my King is my husband.
你的帐篷到了 晚安 贝里席大人
Here is your tent,Lord Baelish. Good night.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
风暴降生 龙之母
这不是你的马
这是十三巨子给我的
他们是魁尔斯城的长者
魁尔斯城？
嗯 往东三日骑乘 在海边
他们会接纳我们吗？
他们说龙之母的大驾光临是他们的无上荣耀
你了解这个地方么？
What do you know of this place?
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊” 流亡骑士
只知道他们的城市被荒漠包围
Only that the desert around their walls
被称作骸骨花园
is called the Garden of Bones.
每当魁尔斯对旅人关闭大门
Every time the Qartheen shut their gates on a traveler,
花园就更加繁荣
the garden grows.
走！你 继续走！
Go on!You, keep moving!
"阿利"
艾莉亚·史塔克
詹德利
“大牛”
热派
赫伦堡
维斯特洛最大的城堡
为铁群岛与河间地之王“黑心”赫伦所修建
征服者战争中被伊耿一世的巨龙所焚毁
带她过来！
Bring her about!
什么火焰才能融化石头？
What kind of fire melts stone?
龙焰
Dragon fire.
这里有龙？
There's dragons here?
没有，所有的龙都已经死了
No, all the dragons are dead.
什么味道？
What's that smell?
死人
Dead people.
走
Move.
求求你 求求你 不要 不要！
Please, please, no, no!
不要
No.
他死了
He's dead.
他是我儿子
He was my son.
我的妹妹死于三天前
My sister was three days ago.
我丈夫比她还早一天
My husband,the day before that.
他们每天挑一个人？
They take someone every day?
有人能活下来么？
Does anyone live?
乔佛里
Joffrey.
瑟曦
Cersei.
伊林·派恩
Ilyn Payne.
注：伊林·佩恩 御前执法官 处死艾德·史塔克的侩子手
猎狗
The Hound.
乔佛里
Joffrey.
瑟曦
Cersei.
伊林·派恩
Ilyn Payne.
猎狗
The Hound.
乔佛里 瑟曦
Joffrey. Cersei.
伊林·派恩 猎狗
Ilyn Payne.The Hound.
凯特琳·徒利
史塔克夫人
你好大的胆子
How dare you?
你也许误会我了
You may have heard false reports.
－你背叛了奈德 －背叛?
- You betrayed Ned. －Betrayed?
我希望他能成为全境守护
I wanted him to serve as Protector of the Realm.
我恳请他抓住机会
I begged him to seize the moment.
我信任你 我丈夫信任你
I trusted you. My husband trusted you.
而你却报以背叛
And you repaid our faith with treachery.
－并非如此 夫人  －滚出去
- No, My Lady.  - Get out!
凯特 我从——
Cat, I've--
我从孩童时期就一直深爱着你
I've loved you since I was a boy.
对我来说 这是命运给予我们的机会——
It seems to me that fate has given us this chance--
你疯了吗？滚出去！
Have you lost your mind?Get out!
你还想再与女儿们相见么？
Do you want to see your girls again?
珊莎 比以前更漂亮
Sansa, more beautiful than ever.
还有艾莉亚 还跟以前一样顽皮
And Arya,just as wild as ever.
艾莉亚也在你手上？
You have Arya, too?
她们都安然无恙
Both girls are healthy and safe...
目前如此
for now.
但是你了解太后和乔佛里
But you know the Queen and you know Joffrey.
若继续留在君临
I fear for their longevity
我担心她们的生命安全
if they remain in the capital.
你想要什么
What do you want?
兰尼斯特愿意用你的女儿来交换弑君者
The Lannisters will trade your daughters for the Kingslayer.
他们当然愿意
Of course they will.
用詹姆·兰尼斯特换两个小丫头？
Jaime Lannister for two girls?
罗柏不可能同意这样的条件
Robb will never agree to those terms.
我不是在跟他讲这些条件
I'm not bringing these terms to him.
而是在跟你讲
I'm bringing them to you.
你认为我会瞒着我儿子？
You think I'd keep secrets from my son?
罗柏的领兵作战 无往不胜 让世人惊叹
Robb has surprised them all with his skills in battle,
但他没做过母亲
but he's not a mother.
考虑一下 凯特
Consider it, Cat.
机会稍纵即逝
You may not get another chance.
- 我还有礼物奉上  - 我不稀罕你的礼物
- I've brought you a gift. - I don't want your gifts.
这礼物是提利昂·兰尼斯特的一番好意
A token of Tyrion Lannister's goodwill.
他想让你知道 这次俘虏交换
He wants you to understand that this exchange of prisoners
完全是真心诚意的
is offered in good faith.
真心诚意？
Good faith?
这是？
What's this?
你丈夫这样的可敬之辈
Your husband was an honorable man.
理应安眠于临冬城下的墓穴 列于族人之侧
He should rest beside his family in the crypts beneath Winterfell.
- 你也许不信——  - 出去
- You may not believe-- - get out.
蠢猪们赶紧起来！
Get up, you dogs!
他来了 来挑人的
That's him, the one who picks.
是魔山
The Mountain.
你这是干什么？
What are you doing?
这人告诉我他每天都直视他
He told me he stares at him every day.
所以才不被挑到
That's why he doesn't get picked.
格雷果·克里冈
“魔山”
你
You.
走了 小子！
Move, boy!
让开！
Move!
村里藏有金子和银子吗？
Is there gold and silver in the village?
- 不知道  - 珠宝呢？
- I don't know. - Gems?
我没有见着
I didn't see any.
- 无旗兄弟会在哪？  - 不知道
- Where is the Brotherhood? - I don't know.
“记事本”
士兵
- 无旗兄弟会在哪？  - 不知道 求您了
- Where is the Brotherhood? - I don't know. Please.
- 无旗兄弟会在哪？  - 我真的不知道
- Where is the Brotherhood? - I don't know.
有哪位村民帮助过他们？
Which of the villagers aided them?
- 不知道  - 谁？
- I don't know. - Who?
我——
I--
- 谁？  - 我没看到
- Who? - I never saw.
- 谁？  - 我没看到啊
求您了 求您住手吧 这家伙就要——
Please. Please, stop. Please, it's starting to--
- 谁？ - 我没看到有人帮助他
- Who? - I didn't see anyone help him.
拿掉吧！拿掉吧！
Take it off! Take it off!
- 谁帮过他？  - 屠夫盖恩斯
- Who helped him? - Ganes the butcher
- 还有他儿子  - 这多好
- and his son. - That's better.
- 你省了我们不少事  - 不 求您住手吧！
- You've been very helpful. - No, stop, please!
你们这是要怎样？求您了 住手吧！
What are you doing? Please, stop!
求您住手啊！啊！啊！
Please, stop!No! No!
我已经全都招了！啊！
I told you everything!No!
啊！
No!
乔佛里
Joffrey.
瑟曦
Cersei.
伊林·派恩 猎狗
Ilyn Payne. The Hound.
波利佛 求求你 给点吃的吧
Please, Polliver. Some food.
一点面包屑也好
Just a crust of bread.
波利佛
士兵
Polliver.
魔山
The Mountain.
史塔克夫人 没想到能在风暴地遇见你
Lady Stark, I had not thought to find you in the Stormlands.
史坦尼斯大人 我也没想到我会来这儿
I had not thought to be here, Lord Stannis.
- 我眼前的真是你？  - 不是我还能是谁？
- Can that truly be you? - Who else might it be?
看见你这旗 我还不大确定呢
When I saw your standard, I couldn't be sure.
- 你打着谁的旗号？  - 我自己的
- Whose banner is that? - My own.
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
在狭海的王
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士”
我还以为咱俩的家徽是一样的呢
I suppose if we used the same one,
那打起仗来可就把人闹糊涂了
the battle would be terribly confusing.
你的鹿怎么被火烤了？
Why is your stag on fire?
此乃国王陛下的家徽
The King has taken for his sigil
梅丽珊卓
缚影士 “光之王”的红袍祭司
光之王的烈焰红心
the fiery heart of the Lord of Light.
哈 你一定就是那个传闻中的火焰祭司了
Ah, you must be this fire priestess we hear so much about.
嗯 哥哥
Mm, brother,
我终于知道是什么让你一把年纪还要拜鬼求神了
now I understand why you found religion in your old age.
蓝礼 你留点神
Watch yourself, Renly.
噢 噢 放轻松
No, no, I'm relieved.
我从没觉得你会如此狂热地迷上宗教
I never really believed you're a fanatic.
没错 你乏味 死板 无趣
Charmless, rigid, a bore, yes,
但绝没有虔诚
but not a godly man.
在你的兄长面前你理应下跪
You should kneel before your brother
he's the Lord's chosen,
他承真主之命
降生于盐与烟之地
born amidst salt and smoke.
降生于盐与烟之地？
Born amidst salt and smoke?
感情他是块火腿？
Is he a ham?
这是我第二次警告你
That's twice I've warned you.
听听你们说的话
Listen to yourselves.
如果你们是我的儿子 我要把你们两个的头狠狠撞在一起
If you were sons of mine, I would knock your heads together
然后锁进一间卧室 直到你们认清
and lock you in a bedchamber until you remembered
彼此是兄弟这事实
that you were brothers.
史塔克夫人 我很好奇为何您会站在我弟弟那边
It is strange to find you beside my brother, Lady Stark.
您丈夫是支持我称王的
Your husband was a supporter of my claim.
史塔克大人为维护正统而献身
Lord Eddard's integrity cost him his head.
你却在这个僭王身边责问我
And you sit beside this pretender and chastise me.
我们有共同的敌人
We share a common enemy.
按照律法 铁王座属于我
The Iron Throne is mine by right.
否认这点的都是我的敌人
All those that deny that are my foes.
从多恩到长城 全境都在否认你啊
The whole realm denies it, from Dorne to the Wall.
糟老头子临死时念叨着否认
Old men deny it with their death rattle
未出生的婴儿在妈妈肚子里踢闹着否认
and unborn children deny it in their mother's wombs.
没人想让你当他的国王
No one wants you for their King.
老哥 你就是不爱交朋友
You never wanted any friends, brother.
但是没有朋友相助 还争什么权力
But a man without friends is a man without power.
看在我们母亲的份上
For the sake of the mother who bore us,
今晚上我给你时间考虑
I will give you this one night to reconsider.
降下叛旗
Strike your banners,
在天亮之前投效于我
come to me before dawn,
我保证你在御前会议仍占一席之地
and I will grant you your old seat in the council.
甚至在我儿子出生之前
I'll even name you my heir
我仍旧把你指定为我的继承人
until a son is born to me.
否则你就只有毁灭一途
Otherwise I shall destroy you.
你仔细看看那边的平原 老哥
Look across those fields, brother.
看到那些旗帜了吗？
Can you see all those banners?
你以为几根绑着破布的棍子就能把你架上王座？
You think a few bolts of cloth will make you King?
不能
No.
可是高举这破布棍子的军队，能让我称王
The men holding those bolts of cloth will make me King.
走着瞧 蓝礼
We shall see, Renly.
天一亮 就见分晓
Come the dawn, we shall see.
记住你自己的罪孽 蓝礼大人
Look to your sins, Lord Renly.
长夜黑暗 处处险恶
The night is dark and full of terrors.
你信吗 我跟他是亲兄弟？
Would you believe I loved him once?
我还以为他们会欢迎我们
I thought we were welcome.
如果你听说一整个多斯拉克部落逼近你的城市
If you heard a Dothraki horde was approaching your city,
你也会这么做的 卡丽熙
you might do the same, Khaleesi.
部落？
Horde?
十三巨子
商会 魁尔斯的实际统治者
我是丹妮莉丝——
My name is Daenerys--
坦格利安家族的“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝
Daenerys Stormborn of the House Targaryen.
大人 您早知道我？
You know me, My Lord?
您名声不小 卡丽熙
Only by reputation, Khaleesi.
而我并非什么大人 只是一介俗商
And I'm no lord, merely a humble merchant.
世人称您为龙之母
They call you the Mother of Dragons.
那么我该怎么称呼您
And what should I call you?
噢 我的名字很长
Oh, my name is quite long
发音对于异国人来更是不易
and quite impossible for foreigners to pronounce.
我只不过是个香料商人
I am simply a trader of spices.
但魁尔斯的管理和守卫
But we are the Thirteen,
却由我们“十三巨子”负责
charged with the governance and protection of Qarth,
这里是古往今来最伟大的城市
the greatest city that ever was or will be.
夸尔斯的壮美令人动容——
The beauty of Quarth is legendary--
是魁尔斯
Qarth.
魁尔斯
我们可否目睹一下真龙？
Might we see the dragons?
我的朋友
My friend,
我们旅途颠簸
we have travelled very far.
水尽粮绝
We have no food, no water.
只要我的子民得以温饱 我将感激不尽 为——
Once I see my people fed, I would be honored--
恕我直言 龙之母
Forgive me, Mother of Dragons,
没人目睹真龙现世
but no man alive has seen a living dragon.
总有些满腹狐疑的朋友
Some of my more skeptical friends
怀疑您的孩子们是否
refuse to believe your children
真的存在
even exist.
我们只是请求亲眼一见
All we ask is the chance to see for ourselves.
我从不说谎
I am not a liar.
哈 我对此毫不怀疑
Oh, I don't think you are.
但是你我素昧谋面
But as I've never met you before,
我的意见可说服不了大家啊
my opinion on the matter is of limited value.
在我的家乡
Where I come from,
迎接宾客的是厅堂内的礼遇
guests are treated with respect,
而非门外的羞辱
not insulted at the gates.
那么 或许您应该启程回乡才是
Then perhaps you should return to where you come from.
祝您一路顺风
We wish you well.
岂有此理？
What are you doing?
你答应了要接待我们
You promised to receive me.
我们是接待了你们
We have received you.
你我同在此 眼下不正是接待？
Here we are, and here you are.
如果你不让我们进城 我们全都活不下去
If you do not let us in, all of us will die.
对此我们深表遗憾
Which we shall deeply regret.
但古往今来
But Qarth did not become
最伟大的魁尔斯城
the greatest city that ever was or will be
岂能为多斯拉克蛮族敞开大门？
by letting Dothraki savages through its gates.
卡丽熙 说话小心
Khaleesi, please be careful.
十三巨子！
Thirteen!
他日吾龙成器
When my dragons are grown,
定将归来取走本应属于我的东西
we will take back what was stolen from me
摧毁那些未曾公正待我之人
and destroy those who have wronged me.
燎原御敌
We will lay waste to armies
怒火焚城
and burn cities to the ground.
拒我于城外者 将第一个葬身火海
Turn us away and we will burn you first.
哈
Ah.
不愧是坦格利安
You are a true Targaryen.
但是 就像你刚才说的那样
Only, as you said a moment ago,
如果我们不让你们进城
if we don't let you into the city,
你们全都活不下去 所以……
you will all die. And so...
一个小姑娘就让你怕得关门大吉
Retreating in fear from a little girl
这作风可配不上
is unbecoming of the greatest city
古往今来最伟大的城市
that ever was or will be.
讨论已经结束了 札罗·赞旺·达梭斯
The discussion is over, Xaro Xhoan Daxos.
十三巨子已经做出决定
The Thirteen have spoken.
我也是十三巨子之一
I am one of the Thirteen
札罗·赞旺·达梭斯
而我还有话要说
and I am still speaking.
这个小女孩威胁说要焚我城池
The girl threatens to burn our city to the ground
难道你想请她入城品酒不成？
and you would invite her in for a cup of wine?
她是龙之母
She is the Mother of Dragons.
你让她眼睁睁地看着子民挨饿
Do you expect her to watch her people starve
岂不唤醒了睡龙之怒？
without breathing fire?
放这区区几个多斯拉克人进城
I believe we can allow a few Dothraki
就会毁了大家不成？
through our gates without dooming our city.
况且 我也是蛮族出身
After all, here I am,
从盛夏群岛到了这里
a savage from the Summer Isles,
可魁尔斯不是屹立如初？
and Qarth still stands.
我们已经决定了
Our decision is final.
很好
Very well.
苏摩依神为证
I invoke Soumai.
我以律法之名
I will vouch for her, her people,
为她 她的子民和她的龙担保
and her dragons in accordance with the law.
此事你得负全责
Be it on your head.
夫人 欢迎来到魁尔斯
Welcome to Qarth, My Lady.
你
You.
村里藏有金子吗？银子呢？
Is there gold or silver in the village?
- 我不是村里人    - 无旗兄弟会在哪？
- I'm not from the village.    - Where is the Brotherhood?
我不知道什么兄弟会
I don't know what that is.
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护
你们两个，把泰温大人的东西送到他的住处
You two, take Lord Lannister's things to his quarters.
这是在干什么？
What's this?
我们以为您明天才会到 泰温大人
We weren't expecting you till tomorrow, Lord Tywin.
显然不是
Evidently not.
为什么不把犯人关进牢房？
Why are these prisoners not in their cells?
牢房已经满了 大人
Cells are overflowing,My Lord.
这群人不会在这呆多久的
This lot won't be here long.
不需要为他们准备固定的牢房
Don't need no permanent place.
审讯完之后 我们通常...
After we interrogate 'em, we usually just...
难道我们人手很多？以致可以
Are we so well-manned that we can afford to discard
把年轻劳力和娴熟工匠弃之不用？
able young bodies and skilled laborers?
你 有什么手艺吗？
You,do you have a trade?
我会打铁 大人
Smith, My Lord.
看什么看！跪下！
What are you looking at?Kneel!
跪下！不然把你的心肺挖出来 小子
Kneel or I'll carve your lungs out, boy.
“他”不会照做的
He'll do no such thing.
这个“他”是个女孩 你这白痴
This one's a girl,you idiot,
穿着男孩的衣服
dressed as a boy.
- 为什么？    - 这样上路比较安全 大人
- Why?    - Safer to travel, My Lord.
聪明
Smart.
这帮贱种里难得出个机灵鬼
More than I can say for this lot.
给这些人安排活干
Get these prisoners to work.
这个女孩跟着我
Bring the girl.
我需要个新侍酒
I need a new cupbearer.
是 大人
My Lord.
你可是稀客 表弟
Your visits are too few, cousin.
摄政太后陛下
Her Grace,the Queen Regent,
命令你即刻释放大学士派席尔
commands you to release Grand Maester Pycelle.
- 这是陛下的授权状   - 原来如此
- Here's your warrant.   - So it is.
陪我喝一杯如何？
Will you take a cup with me?
我发现温酒有助于睡眠
I find that mulled wine helps me sleep.
我代表陛下前来宣令
I am here at her Grace's behest,
不是来跟你喝酒的 小恶魔
not to drink with you, Imp.
如果我亲爱的姐姐真那么在乎派席尔
If my sister was so concerned for Pycelle,
我想她似乎该亲自来
I would have thought she'd come herself.
但她却派了你
Instead she sends you.
对此 我该作何理解？
What am I to make of that?
随你怎么理解
I don't care what you make of it,
只须你马上放人
so long as you release your prisoner immediately.
你是直接从瑟曦那里得到的命令？
And you've received these instructions directly from Cersei?
我说了不止一次
As I said several times.
而你却等了这么久才来传达这消息？
And you've waited this long to deliver the information?
摄政太后给我下达命令之后
When the Queen Regent gives me a command, I carry
我毫无延误地将其带给你
it out without delay.
瑟曦对你的信任可见一斑
Cersei must have great trust in you,
在狼时这么个当口
allowing you into her chamber
还允许你进她的房间
during the hour of the wolf.
摄政太后重任在肩
The Queen Regent has a great many responsibilities.
忙于公事 常常通宵达旦
She often works from dusk till dawn.
有你通宵达旦地帮她
She must be very glad to have you helping her
她一定非常欢喜
from dusk till dawn.
啊 薰衣草精油
Ah, lavender oil.
打小她就喜欢薰衣草精油
She always loved lavender oil, even as a girl.
我是名骑士！
I am a Knight!
难怪 抹了圣油的骑士啊
An anointed Knight, yes.
告诉我 瑟曦封你作骑士
Tell me, did Cersei have you knighted
是上床前还是上床后呐？
before or after she took you into her bed?
怎么？没话说了？
What? Nothing to say?
就不会对我来点抗议么 爵士？
No more warnings for me, Ser?
你必须收回这些下流的指控
You will withdraw these filthy accusations.
拜托 你有没有想过
Have you ever given any thought
假如我告诉乔佛里你睡了他老妈
to what King Joffrey will have to say
他又会有何看法呢？
when he finds out you've been bedding his mother?
这错不在我！
It's not my fault!
是她强迫的你？
Did she take you against your will?
你不会自卫吗 骑士？
Can you not defend yourself, Knight?
是您父亲 泰温大人 从我当上国王的侍从那天起
Your own father, Lord Tywin, when I was named the King's squire,
他就嘱咐我一切听太后差遣
he told me to obey her in everything.
包括嘱咐你和她上床？
Did he tell you to fuck her, too?
我只是以为 我只是奉命
I only meant I did as I was bid.
但是却痛恨这一切
Hated every moment of it,
你指望我相信这个？
is that what you'll have me believe?
朝廷的高位 骑士的身份
A high place in court, a knighthood,
我姐姐夜里为你张开的双腿
my sister's legs spreading open for you at night.
哦 是啊 这一切对你来说太糟糕了
Oh, yes, it must have been terrible.
等在这里 等国王陛下来亲自裁决
Wait here. His Grace will want to hear this.
发发慈悲吧！大人 求求您
Mercy! Mercy, My Lord! I beg you.
省省吧 这些话给乔佛里说去 他最喜欢听别人苦苦哀求
Save it for Joffrey. He loves a good grovel.
大人 这些都是令姐
My Lord, it was your sister's bidding--
太后陛下的命令
the Queen.
我会立刻离开都城 我发誓
I'll leave the city at once, I swear.
- 我想不必     - 大人？
- No, I think not.    - My Lord?
没错
You heard me.
我父亲不是要你听她差遣么
My father told you to obey my sister.
那就照办
Obey her.
留在她的身边 保持她的信任
Stay close to her side. Keep her trust.
随时满足她的需求
Pleasure her whenever she requires.
之前的事情不会有人知道
No one ever need know
只要你忠诚于我
as long as you keep faith with me.
作为回报 我想知道瑟曦在干什么
I want to know what Cersei is doing,
去了哪里 见了谁
where she goes, who she sees,
她有什么计划  所有的一切
what they talk of-- everything.
你都必须告诉我
And you will tell me.
行 大人 我会的
Yes, My Lord, I will.
我发誓 照您说的做
I swear it, as you command.
哦 起来 起来吧
Oh, rise, rise.
为我们的共识干一杯
Let us drink to our understanding.
哦 你没有杯子 那就算了
Oh, you don't have a cup. Oh, well.
开心点 堂弟 我姐姐是个大美人
Smile, cousin. My sister is a beautiful woman.
而你做的一切都是为了国家
And it's all for the good of the realm.
回去告诉她 我恳求她的原谅
Go back and tell her that I beg her forgiveness,
我不希望我们之间有任何矛盾
that I want no more conflict between us
从今往后
and that henceforth
未经她同意 我不会轻举妄动
I shall do nothing without her consent.
但她要求...
But her demands.
噢 我会把派席尔还给她
Oh, I'll give her Pycelle.
- 您会吗？    -是的 我明天就放人
- You will?    - Yes, I'll release him in the morning.
如果她愿意 瑟曦可以把他当宠物养
Cersei can keep him as a pet if she wants,
但是绝不能让他留在御前会议
but I will not have him on the council.
我可以保证 他毫“发”无伤
I could swear that I had not harmed a single hair on his head,
不过严格说起来 这不算实话
but that would not, strictly speaking, be true.
保持船距 保持队形
Stay within one table length.
陛下
Your Grace.
你的指骨给你带来好运了吗？
Do your knucklebones bring you luck?
自从您把它们切下来后我的生活一直都不赖 陛下
Well, life's been good since you hacked them off, Your Grace.
而且省了清理四坨指甲的功夫
And it's four less fingernails to clean.
- 四枚    - 什么？
- Fewer.    - Pardon?
省了清理四枚指甲的功夫
Four fewer fingernails to clean.
不明白你为什么要一直带着它们
Never understood why you had to wear them.
它提醒着我曾经的出身 我现在的身份
It reminds me of where I come from and where I am now.
以及您的公正无私
It reminds me of your justice.
您对我的惩罚很公正
It was an honest punishment
而且切肉的刀您也用的很好
and you were good with the cleaver.
你既是个英雄也是个走私贩
You were a hero and a smuggler.
善行并不能抵消恶行
A good act does not wash out the bad,
恶行也不能掩盖善行
nor a bad the good.
这正是我想让我儿子学到的
A lesson I've tried to teach my son.
- 他听你的吗？    - 听我的？
- Does he listen?    - To me?
从来都不
Gods, no.
但如果是您的红袍女让他从鸦巢上跳下去...
But if your red woman told him to leap from the crow's nest--
她有名字
She has a name.
我想你还没有忘记走私者的把戏吧
I trust you've not forgotten your smuggler's tricks.
我已奉公守法生活了十七...
I've lived within the law for 17--
我需要你再做一次走私者
I want you to be a smuggler this time.
随时随地都可以
Any shore, any night.
需要我走私什么？
What am I bringing ashore?
红袍女
The red woman.
不许告诉任何人
No one must know what you do
我们也不会再次谈论这事
and we'll not speak of this again.
我是您忠诚的仆人 陛下 永远都是
I am true to Your Grace and always will be,
但肯定还有别的办法 更讲求荣誉的办法
but surely there are other ways, cleaner ways.
讲求荣誉无法赢得战争
Cleaner ways don't win wars.
你害怕吗 洋葱骑士
Are you afraid,onion knight?
有人告诉我
Someone once told me
长夜黑暗 处处险恶
the night is dark and full of terrors.
做走私贩的时候你曾运过更讨厌的货物吧
You've carried more unpleasant cargo in your time.
你是个好人吗 戴佛斯·席沃斯爵士？
Are you a good man,Ser Davos Seaworth?
我只能说说我是个复杂的人 夫人
I'd say my parts are mixed, My Lady--
好坏参半
good and bad.
如果一个洋葱有一半腐烂发黑
If half an onion is black with rot,
那它就是一个烂洋葱
it's a rotten onion.
一个人非善即恶
A man is good or he is evil.
- 那么你是？      -哦 当然是好人
- And which are you?   - Oh, good.
我也算是个骑士
I'm a Knight myself of sorts,
为光明和生命而战的骑士
a champion of light and life.
哦 那对你来说一定感觉不错
Well, that must be very nice for you.
- 你爱自己的妻子吗？    -是的
- Do you love your wife?    - I do.
但你却结识过其他的女人
Yet you have known other women.
别扯上我的妻子
Don't talk about my wife.
我没有说她 我是说其他女人
I'm not. I'm talking about other women.
比如我 戴佛斯爵士
Like me, Ser Davos.
你想要我
You want me.
你想看这长袍下的身体
You want to see what's beneath this robe.
你会看到的
And you will.
光之王真是奇怪
Strange that this Lord of Light
竟然让您在暗影中行事
asks you to work in the shadows.
黑暗处可是没有影子的 戴佛斯爵士
Shadows cannot live in the dark, Ser Davos.
影子是光明的仆人
They are servants of light,
烈焰的子孙
the children of fire.
惟有最耀眼的火光 方能映照出最黑暗的阴影
And the brighter the flame,the darker they are.
这里本来没有栅栏 他们堵住了通道
These weren't here before.They've barred the passage.
这阻挡不了我们
They can't bar our passage.
诸神保佑
Gods protect us.
只有一位真神 戴佛斯爵士
There's only one God,Ser Davos,
他只保佑侍奉他的人
and he only protects those who serve him.
衣柜字幕组出品